VIJAYAKUMAR BANGARU

Sr.Service Engg( CCTV & KIOSK ) and Technical Sales Executive

kumarvijayvvv@outlook.com

Mobile: +91-9944256090

Mail:

**OBJECTIVE** 

Acquire a career in the IT Field where I can utilize my various computers, technological, and

customer service skills.

**PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY** 

I am a responsible, creative and hands on technical support with more than 5 years of

experience operating system (Windows).

Qualified to IT industry standards, myself updating and tracking the latest technologies and

apply them to my duties wherever possible.

**TECHNOLOGY STACK** 

**Tools** : AnyDesk and Teamviewer

**Package** : MS Office(Excel functions V lookup, H lookup and pivot table)

: Windows - Windows XP/Vista/7/8/8.1/10 Operating Systems

**WORK EXPERIENCE Coustomer support Engineer** 

Company: AGS transact technologies

Web site: https://www.agsindia.com/

**Company Description:** 

AGS transact technologies one of the largest integrated omni-channel payment solutions

providers in India in terms of providing digital and cash-based solutions to banks and

corporate clients. (Source: Ken Research Report). We provide customised products and

services comprising ATM and Cash Recycler Machines (CRM) outsourcing, cash management and digital payment solutions including merchant solutions, transaction processing services

and mobile wallets.

Client : BANKING SECTORS

Duration : 12th OCT 2023 to Till date

Role : Coustomer Support Engineer

#### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITY**

- Responsible for providing installation, maintenance, and repairs on equipment (ATM/PoS Machine, E-Surveillance Device & Online UPS) within an assigned territory/region/location to assure continuity of customer operations and high levels of customer satisfaction
- SLM calls should be attended within TAT, as per agreed SLA
- Carry out Preventive Maintenance of all assigned ATM machines every quarter and submit related documents at the company office
- Assist in site preparation including cable installation, staging and standard testing and commissioning of e-surveillances equipment
- Maintain inventory of parts and related records
- · Provide status reports throughout the service
- Diagnose problems based on the information provided in assigned call as well as working with the customer to determine all issues at the site
- Manage customer issues until resolution according to SLA agreements

## **WORK EXPERIENCE [Sr.Field Technician]**

1) Company: Botree Software International Pvt. Limited (<u>RedSky Technologies</u>)
Web site: <a href="https://botreesoftware.com/">https://botreesoftware.com/</a> and <a href="https://botreesoftware.com/">https://botreesoftware.com/</a>

#### **Company Description:**

RedSky Technologies is aggregating Retail by using disaggregated digitized data, with their patented plug n play device. Through our unified platform for all retail services, CPG companies can mimic the strategies used by the online players to bring in the efficiencies and improve product and pricing. Apart from building smart product strategies, CPG companies can plan and make their inventory management, production planning and distribution strategies much more agile as now the data would be available to them instantly.

Client : Retail Shops

**Duration**: 26<sup>th</sup> OCT 2020 to Till date

Role : Sr. Field Technician and Technical Sales Executive

## **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITY**

- Partnering with stores and Generating new leads
- Evaluating the client's behaviour Managing relationship with existing clients

Ensuring active participation from enrolled stores

Managing sales process through a CRM system

• Installation of company's setup at partner stores ,Maintenance and troubleshooting technical

issues reported at stores

Reporting of new technical challenges faced in the field Maintain record of actions at each

store visit in CRM software

Remote desktop connection and Remote assistance Providing technical support for day to

day work

• Installation and implementation of desktop computing devices, printers and other peripheral

devices, and wireless computing and communications devices.

Working of and experience in the Financial Services industry and its regulations

Performs other duties assigned.

Work with individuals in a virtual, multi-vendor and multi-cultural environment with different

level of technical understanding; should be able to adjust communication style based on

targeted audience

Analyse customer needs, document requirements, and design technical solutions.

**WORK EXPERIENCE [Sr.Service Engineer]** 

**Company: Aurionpro Solutions Ltd** 

Web site: www.aurionpro.com

**Company Description:** 

Aurionpro Solutions Limited is a global technology solutions company. The Company is

engaged in offering information technology (IT) and consultancy services. It is also

engaged in the sale of equipment and software licenses. It is engaged in the business of

providing solutions in corporate banking, treasury, fraud prevention and risk management,

Internet banking, governance and compliance. Its geographic segments include India. It is

a provider of intellectual property-led IT solutions for the banking and financial service

insurance segments. It also provides self-service technologies, which enable financial

institutions, utilities, telecom and government organization.

Client : Banking and financial services

**Duration**: Aug 2015 to Oct 2020

Role : Sr.Service Engineer

**ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITY** 

• CCTV Installation and Configuration (Working in Delhi CCTV GOVT project)

- Co-ordinate With Field Engineers and Add the IP Camera's details in CCC Server(Central Command Center PWD office)
- Data Backup and Restoration Procedures
- Helps in the installation process of new and advanced technologies interpreting the requirements
- Give the Training to the bank person about Self-service Kiosk
- Managing any kind of technical work at the field even with little supervision
- Ability to communicate fluently with the customers and should possess good customer service skills
- Maintaining Incident report system during System downtime
- Networking and crimping
- Network and TCP/IP Configuration and Troubleshooting
- Remote desktop connection and Remote assistance
- Providing technical support for day to day Banking
- Maintains reports of and hands to the senior and concerned

# Company: BILDScribe BPO India Pvt Ltd

Web site: <a href="http://www.bildscribe.com">http://www.bildscribe.com</a>

### **Company Description:**

BILDScribe BPO India Pvt Ltd is the domestic call centre that provides inbound & outbound process, data entry process and English language academy. We deliver data processing, inbound process for one of the leading telecom industry.

## Project 1:

Client : Aircel (Inbound Process)

**Duration**: July 2013 to July 2015

Role : Desktop Support Administrator

## **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITY**

Hardware Maintenance and Replacement

Windows Operating System Installations: Windows XP, Windows Vista, and Windows 7

Windows Operating System Configurations and Troubleshooting

Network and TCP/IP Configuration and Troubleshooting

Printer Installation and configuring network printers

Basic networking and crimping

Troubleshooting internet and intranet systems

Remote desktop connection and Remote assistance

Antivirus installation on client and server end

Providing solutions to the day to day problems of the users

# Project 2:

Client : English language academy (Outbound Process)

**Duration**: May 2014 to July 2015

Role : Desktop support Administrator

### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITY**

✓ Managed over 150 PCs in a Windows environment

- ✓ Configured PCs to be joined to local area networks and domains
- ✓ Installation and configuration of Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 8.1
- ✓ Troubleshooting software and hardware related concerns
- ✓ Disk management and partition
- ✓ Folder sharing and mapping into drive
- ✓ Followed specific internal design specifications and met specific deadlines

✓

#### **EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

- ✓ Active Co-ordination in our department symposium.
- ✓ Zone level CRICKET PLAYER and secured prizes for well playing.

#### **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION**

- ✓ BE (ECE) from Tamilnadu College of Engineering, Anna University Coimbatore in 2009-2013.
- ✓ HSC from N.S.Boys Hr. Sec School, Theni in 2008-2009.
- ✓ SSLC from N.S.Boys Hr. Sec School, Theni in 2006-2007.

### PERSONAL PROFILE

Date of Birth : 02/01/1992
Father's Name. : R.Bangaru
Marital Status : Married

Languages Known : Tamil, English, and Telugu

Hobbies : Playing cricket, drawing (3D drawing)

#### **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.

Place: Coimbatore	Sincerely,
Date:	(Vijayakumar B)